<resources>

    <string name="data"> is evident from Eq 5.8.34, that envelope A(0) which appears at the output of the envelope
                 detector has no exclusive term proportional to the baseband (modulating) signal f(t). The term
                 N is multiplied with a large noise term cos 6(0) and hence, f(t) cannot be separated from the
                 noise. As the modulating term/ () 1s Completely mingled with noise, it carries no useful information.
                 The loss of the message f (t) in an envelope detector due to the presence of the large noise is
                 referred to as the threshold effect.
                 5:9 COMPARISON OF VARIOUS AM SYSTEMS
                 (5.8.33)
                 We have seen that when a noise in large as compared to the signal at the input of the envelope
                 detector, the detected output has a message signal completely mingled with the noise. It means
                 that if the input signal-to-noise ratio (S, / N) is below a certain level, called threshold level, the
                 nOise dominates over the message signal. Threshold is defined as value of the input signal to
                 nOise ratio (S,/ N) below which the output signal to noise ratio (S, / N,) deteriorates much more
                 rapidly than the input signal to noise ratio. The threshold effect starts in an envelope detector
                 Whenever the carrier power to noise power ratio approaches unity or less. It is important to stress
                 that the threshold effect is the property of an envelope detector; on the other hand, such an effect
                 Snot observed in a synchronous detector (Prob. 5.13).
                 (5.8.34)
                 lar we have studied the various forms of amplitude modulation, accordingly we can divide
                 no two broad categories, viz. suppressed carrier AM system; and AM systems witha large
                 r amplitude. The suppressed carrier system can be further subdivided into three parts: (a)
                 (b) SSB-SC; and © VSB-SC, It is worthwhile to compare the various AM systems
                 tased on the following points:
                 For the receiver, an AM is advantageous, because the envelope detector used in such a receiver is
                 Very Simple and inexpensive. Therefore, the AM system is preferably used in public communication
                 Sems where a transmitter is associated with a large number of receivers. The receivers cost is
                 portant in such cases, as, for example, in a radio broadcast system, a receiver is needed almost in
                 b ow. ANM system with a large carrier are advantageous in this case. The receivers of a suppressed
                 y house, and can be treated as an essential commodity. Therefore, the cost of the receiver must
                 system are complex and costly as they need additional synchronizing circuits. Therefore.
                 Pressed carrier system is undesirable for public communication systems.</string>

</resources>